[SPEAKER_01]: root series of routine questions I ask.
[SPEAKER_01]: I might start out with this.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is not Stars in Kitchen.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't want to... That's a good story.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell me, were you born here in Brownwood or nearby?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was born in Dallas, and she was born... She said, leave her out of this.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was born March the 2nd.
[SPEAKER_01]: It says 1907.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you come from a ball-playing family at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a brother that was a great football player.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was eight years older than me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he play college ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Me?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he, your brother?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he just played football.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I did, in the Sunday school, the day we go to, I went to, I was a basketball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was tall and slender and could jump.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I played baseball too, sandlot baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I checked my, I checked off my... Is this running now?
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'll run it over and fix you out.
[SPEAKER_00]: After Sunday school, I went with another group
[SPEAKER_00]: out in another area on Sunday afternoon.
[SPEAKER_00]: My mother didn't know about it and neither did anybody else.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I pitched a no-hit, no-run ball game with the Jewish people that I was playing against.
[SPEAKER_00]: All the ballplayers on the Dallas Ball Club was coming down, going into their park.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we worked with about two blocks from the ballpark down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, they stopped and watched me pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: What year would this have been now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: About 2006 or 5?
[SPEAKER_00]: Walter Morris was the manager, not the manager, but he was the owner of the franchise, and he was a friend of mine and lived about three blocks away from my house.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so they all stopped.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I pitched the no-hit, no-run ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so they stayed all that time at Walter Morris.
[SPEAKER_00]: I sent the other players on by to get their workout started.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Walter Morris got me later and asked me to come
[SPEAKER_00]: I worked out with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I can't do that because I'm still going to SMU.
[SPEAKER_00]: And my son is school playing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I can come.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was working.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was in the summertime.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was working with an insurance company.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he helped me get away from the
[SPEAKER_00]: I came on down, and they had to get me a suit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was young enough that
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know what to do half the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they put me in a uniform and an old catcher, the manager, Snipe Conley.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if you remember him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He died here just a few days ago, a few weeks ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he told this old
[SPEAKER_00]: It's been so dang long I'm trying to put things together so you can adjust it anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: I like to do this chronologically.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what I'm trying to figure out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Take your time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Going on with warming up and pitching to the catcher, old man catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I didn't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd throw a fastball, fastball, fastball, and I didn't know what a curve was.
[SPEAKER_00]: as far as that knows, but then I had a knuckle curve.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was quick and broke snap.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I put up about half a dozen pitches to him, fastballs, and got everything over the plate and under good control.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I flipped that
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a fingernail deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: Curve.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it just popped and hit him right in the shin.
[SPEAKER_00]: It fractured it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fractured it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hit him right.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't have any protection.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they signed me after a week.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was your salary?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember that?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not yet.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mr. Morris, the owner of the ball club at that time, gave me a $200 bonus to sign and $200 a month.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they wanted me to learn something and be able to work instead of using all one arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, here's... That's the first steers.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a pack miller,
[SPEAKER_00]: home runner, and Scott Perry, a good old time pitcher, and this is a shortstop, I forget his name, this is Bud Huntling, that was a catcher, and this is another pitcher, Mason, this is another pitcher, and this is big, tall, slim love.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then this is me, and
[SPEAKER_00]: the rest don't amount to anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well that was a good catcher, Charlie Berry.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this was a catcher, Josh Bishop.
[SPEAKER_00]: Josh Bishop.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is a 26, 1926.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1926.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's check and see how we're coming through here now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, you remember the name of that shortstop in that picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was his name again?
[SPEAKER_00]: Turkey Gross.
[SPEAKER_00]: These were all old timers on the Dallas Ball Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just pitched batting practice for about a week.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they sent me down to Corsicana.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I pitched, the first day I pitched, I pitched a no-hit, no-run ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was going with my wife then.
[SPEAKER_00]: We weren't married though.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had an inter-urban at that time, from Dallas to Mahea.
[SPEAKER_00]: I caught on at Corsicana.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got my 50 cents worth up to the, on the N-Urban.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Walter Morris had already heard about the no-hit, no-run ball game all daylight.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he kept me there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was 1926.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, 1926.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we married in 1927.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to get another $200.
[SPEAKER_00]: But left-hander Dara and myself being right-handed, we won the Texas League season and we went down to New Orleans to play
[SPEAKER_00]: The Dixie Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this guy with me and myself that was supposed to go to pitch batting practice, well, the trainer forgot our uniforms.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we sat up there in the grandstand.
[SPEAKER_00]: in a box seat.
[SPEAKER_00]: You never had a seat in a box seat in your life.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we got back home.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't pitch then in the Dixie Series?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I didn't down in New Orleans, but I did back in one game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Excuse me a moment.
[SPEAKER_01]: You went down to Corsicana just for the one game?
[SPEAKER_01]: After the no-hitter, they pulled you right back.
[SPEAKER_00]: They pulled me right back.
[SPEAKER_01]: And what league was that in, East Texas?
[SPEAKER_01]: That was in the Central Texas.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was Class A?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, that was Class B. Oh, Class D. Class D. And the Texas League was Class A then, probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, Texas League was Class A. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, but they won the pennant that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: They won the pennant.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was your record?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember in 26?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, what?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you pitch very much?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched every other day, practically.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't have too many pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Scott Perry and Slim Love?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that was in that picture there, but they were most all of those most over the hill.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, of course, at Canada, they brought me up.
[SPEAKER_00]: from Corsicana.
[SPEAKER_00]: What about that no-hitter at Corsicana?
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a big thrill, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Lord, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they hit any hard ones off you, or was it you're pretty in control the whole way?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's too far gone.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's 1926.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, but.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that was something to start off with.
[SPEAKER_01]: OK, you're back at Dallas now in the Dixie Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got any game there?
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get into it because they had the old time players and they didn't want me to get hurt or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we won, we beat them four times.
[SPEAKER_00]: They went down there, see it was a four of seven.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went down there first for two, came back for two or what had to be done.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so we won four straight.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I pitched batting practice in the two games, but I didn't play any of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the next year, Snipe Conley was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the next year, they fired Snipe and got a
[SPEAKER_00]: a louse as manager because he didn't like young ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Can you mention his name?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll have to remember it later on.
[SPEAKER_00]: This new manager, during spring training,
[SPEAKER_00]: He just released me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so I had an awful good friend that had been a ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an elderly man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in our church.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he heard about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was making himself a scout.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he sent me to Palestine, Texas.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there,
[SPEAKER_00]: I won 16 ballgames.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was a short season, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, it was Class D. You had the same leg as Carson Cannon?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Central Texas.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so they sold me to the San Francisco Seals.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they sent me right then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Off to Seattle.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was this during the 27th season?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, during the 27th season.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so I'd never ridden one of those choo-choos.
[SPEAKER_00]: Scared to death and in a way.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had you been away from home much before?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's kind of a new experience.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just right around Dallas here, right there.
[SPEAKER_00]: played basketball, and I never did play any football.
[SPEAKER_00]: Q.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go to Southern Methodist?
[SPEAKER_00]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I worked and didn't get to get to work.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had my schedule at S.N.U.
[SPEAKER_00]: arranged to where my classes stopped at noon.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I got an
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a job with an insurance man that was a friend of mine, life insurance.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you plan to study?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a major field?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was going to study for a doctor.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I got out of that system right quick.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a pretty tough field, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you...
[SPEAKER_01]: Baseball is the reason you didn't go back then after the second year?
[SPEAKER_01]: You were playing ball by then, was that... Yeah, I was...
[SPEAKER_01]: So you didn't go back to Southern Memphis for... No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I... Well, I went back.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I had too much to do at the insurance company.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just forgot everything going to school again.
[SPEAKER_00]: And...
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about going out to Seattle now with the SEALs.
[SPEAKER_00]: A. I didn't go to the SEALs, except – oh, I see what you mean.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I went back to the SEALs.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first one was the missions.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went with the missions first.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, 60 years gone.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did the missions play in the same ballpark as the SEALs?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, after they built the SEALs ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the missions were nothing but a beer-drinking field.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we had a lot of fun.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never drank any beer.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the manager out there at the missions?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not Bill Killifer, but Greg.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wade.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they then started building a new stadium in San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they got this George Burns, an old first baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He became the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: For some reason or other, he didn't like me.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he fired me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this in 27 now?
[SPEAKER_01]: 27.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: You finished out the season with admissions in 27.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: 28.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was 28 in that spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there was a new field had already been fixed.
[SPEAKER_00]: scout was out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had seen me pitch the year before.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was two, I mean, one other pitcher besides me that George Burns had kicked us out.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't want any
[SPEAKER_00]: Any young players.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't like young players.
[SPEAKER_00]: I better stop saying that.
[SPEAKER_00]: My wife slapped me down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was the scout?
[SPEAKER_00]: Willis Butler.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an elderly man.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had just been fired.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had just been fired from the ball club there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he came up to me and said, let me watch you warm up and what you can show me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I might be able to help you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was a scout in the California area for
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll get it in a minute.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a Wichita fault.
[SPEAKER_00]: But instead, they decided I was good enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, that was the Texas league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they needed a good right-handed pitcher in Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they sent me to Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: They jumped me to $400.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, the scout?
[SPEAKER_01]: The scout, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had really solely the Milwaukee or he made the deal?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he was in, he was the scout for that.
[SPEAKER_01]: For Wichita Falls?
[SPEAKER_00]: Wichita Falls and Milwaukee too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he fixed it that I would, I'd better go there instead of Texas.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because that's too close to my home.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the 28th season now that you're up at Milwaukee?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: 28th, 29th, and 30th.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where's the manager up there?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll have to look here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, we can probably find it.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'll probably think of it in a little while.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right, right.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'll talk about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Killefer, then, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, isn't that a nifty little picture?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, there it is right there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although he's wearing the mission's uniform.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, it says, not will go to steers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sunday for trial on the mound.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't get to Dallas.
[SPEAKER_01]: So Bill Killifer was in Milwaukee?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that what you're saying?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Killifer was with the missions.
[SPEAKER_00]: Franco O'Rourke didn't come until one went to Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, Franco O'Rourke.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Brown's third baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: The old Brown's Third Basement?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, he sure was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good one, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what have we got?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, up in Milwaukee now, in 1928, how'd you do that year?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I did good all three.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't want to mark the table.
[SPEAKER_00]: San Francisco shipped me here.
[SPEAKER_01]: talking about Milwaukee now and 28.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'm a little bit wrong in this.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sent me first to
[SPEAKER_00]: Q.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're not running now, are you?
[SPEAKER_01]: A. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: The missions sent me to Chattanooga.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we did good in San Francisco for the missions.
[SPEAKER_00]: called me back after they saw I had the stuff to go to at the Southern League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you don't care about seeing no one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Joe Engel down at Chattanooga?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Engel.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Joe Engel.
[SPEAKER_00]: The barnum of baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is our manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Chattanooga in 27.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's in 27.
[SPEAKER_00]: They brought me back again.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, after that, I went into Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a good triple-A.
[SPEAKER_00]: So this is from the...
[SPEAKER_00]: It's Locals to Another Wind over Georges.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's 5-2, but...
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, now you got Milwaukee there for... Yeah, I've got... 28...
[SPEAKER_00]: These here are young pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack McDonald wrote this.
[SPEAKER_00]: That Knott's pitching has had considerable to do with
[SPEAKER_00]: with what might jokingly be referred to as a missions pennant drive at Killiford.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're still in luck for it, instead of getting Jim Turner, who was an awful good pitcher, with the missions.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the one that went up to the Boston Bees when he was 30 years old and won 20 games.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wonder why he was down so long.
[SPEAKER_01]: He helped me.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was going to ask you that as a young pitcher coming up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the old timers try to help you or just not tell you anything because you might take their job away?
[SPEAKER_01]: You hear a lot about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was worse then than now.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Turner did help you though.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was an exception to that rule.
[SPEAKER_00]: It made me feel good enough that I can
[SPEAKER_00]: It didn't bother me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to be knocked out or anything else.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did your curveball develop then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used fingernails.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you throw a lot of spitballs?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, only one or two.
[SPEAKER_00]: You obeyed the rules, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Only one or two.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't do any spitballs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd just get it back behind the neck like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's his missions in Portland.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's still in the Coast League.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pretty good record out with the missions apparently there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember any one lost record at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I don't.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got some averages in there, don't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, here's where I got with the Brewers in Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Jack Demge came, and this is our manager there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was he again?
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see if he's in here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Willis Butler.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no, he was the scout.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the scout, but he came up there because he
[SPEAKER_00]: He recommended me to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, Missions fire young hurlers, stars in the east.
[SPEAKER_00]: That'll teach them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had two good years there, and then St. Louis Brown brought me up.
[SPEAKER_00]: They owned
[SPEAKER_01]: The Milwaukee Club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this Ernest Borchardt?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any dealings with him at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was almost dead when I got there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And your ballpark was?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was Borchardt Park.
[SPEAKER_01]: Borchardt Park.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that a good ballpark to pitch in?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it didn't bother me much.
[SPEAKER_00]: It must have been.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was just like this, with high fields.
[SPEAKER_00]: high boards, fences, but they're only about 200 feet down the line.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they got a lot of home runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Center field was much deeper, but the foul lines were short.
[SPEAKER_00]: The foul lines were short.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess it wouldn't be over 150 feet.
[SPEAKER_00]: Until it would go over the fence.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to make it go in the center field.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had to be careful.
[SPEAKER_01]: You couldn't pitch inside to the left-hand hitters.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you pitch against Joe Hauser that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: I spent about three hours with him one day.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's up in Sheboygan, Wisconsin.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1930 was one of his good years.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit over 60 homers that year.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you must have got some insight to him, maybe.
[SPEAKER_00]: He started there in Dallas in 1927.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Nick Collip?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember pitching to Nick?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't bother me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you pitch to him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, he was a power hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched him right here, right over his belly, right in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was getting a little heavy.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's up in Columbus now, in Columbus, Ohio, not far from where we live.
[SPEAKER_00]: You remember the great Shires?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, did you know him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was...
[SPEAKER_00]: He was as good as he thought he was?
[SPEAKER_00]: He sure was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd spray.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't hit very long.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a tough player to handle, I expect.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he was easy going.
[SPEAKER_00]: If anybody goes after him, he's going to get hurt.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nice chap.
[SPEAKER_00]: We liked him fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: And his little wife, the same.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't live too far from here, did they?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, they lived in Dallas.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Shires came back, when he came back from baseball, he had a dining room up on a hill down in North Dallas.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was good.
[SPEAKER_01]: He did some prize fighting, I guess, too, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or professional wrestling?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he didn't do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: As far as I know, if anybody wanted to hit at him or something, he'd go after him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where did you play with him?
[SPEAKER_00]: At Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a spray hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: he'd hit that ball all over the place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too far, but he just sprayed that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was always in the 300.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you remember Luke Boone from Louisville or Minneapolis?
[SPEAKER_00]: Boone.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boone, B-O-O-N-E, not Ike Boone.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Luke Boone who was the instructor of Minneapolis for a while there.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I can remember him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about how the Browns got you then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, because the Browns were the main part of Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: They owned or worked with Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so that's how I got to the majors.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I saw in there in your scrapbook it said they signed you in 1931.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you didn't start pitching with them until 33.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where were you those two years?
[SPEAKER_00]: Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was Milwaukee, 31 and 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: 31 and 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And 28, 29 and 30, you also?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, 29 and 30.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sounds like you were there four years long.
[SPEAKER_01]: Would that be right?
[SPEAKER_01]: I should have brought my other encyclopedia along, but I don't have it.
[SPEAKER_00]: majors in 1933.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had two years with Bill Walters.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was 29.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you feel going up to the big leagues now, after all these years in the Texas League and Coast League?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I figured I could do the job.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was managing the Browns then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Killiford.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did he treat you when you got up there?
[SPEAKER_01]: He never did talk anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just said, let's go out and get them boys, that's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good old man.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the players, do you remember, in the team when you first went up?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I'll have to get...
[SPEAKER_01]: This is a Milwaukee view.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, that's a beautiful scrapbook.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ted Gillick?
[SPEAKER_01]: I always liked that name.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Burns, is he first baseman there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was first baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Oscar Maleno, I guess, was still there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oscar Maleno?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good second baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, boy, he was funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a funny guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Telling jokes or stuff he'd do?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was sure good.
[SPEAKER_01]: He kept the team loose, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he kept them loose.
[SPEAKER_01]: What would he do?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember anything he did?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just liked to play ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he knew how to play it.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about your shortstop, Red Crest?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was at first.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jim Levy, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jim who?
[SPEAKER_00]: Levy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he came after.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he couldn't hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we, uh, Killefer's hurlers and defense stopped street's men.
[SPEAKER_00]: Milwaukee ballpark was, most of the ball players didn't like it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But with me, the center field was the longest.
[SPEAKER_00]: The center field was the only real long park.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'd change up, hit a
[SPEAKER_00]: put a fly ball, and I always, in that part, I didn't want to fool anything except make them run and catch them.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about your outfield on there at St. Louis when you joined them?
[SPEAKER_01]: At Golick?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Fred Scholey?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fred Scholey?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_01]: Heidi Minouche or Bruce Gosling or any of them with the Browns?
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess they were with Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was with Washington all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know who your left fielder was.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Julius Solers, did he come in there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, Moose Solers.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He passed away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he did?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He became blind, you know, had a couple of strokes and heart attacks.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Killifer was my first manager in the Major's.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Killifer.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was this fellow here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Dick Coffman.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was a left-hander.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wally Hebert.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was over in Louisiana.
[SPEAKER_01]: Went by his home there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this Georgian down there, I forget his name.
[SPEAKER_00]: Number seven.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another would be in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lloyd Brown.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Lloyd Brown, left-hander.
[SPEAKER_00]: He moved around, played a lot of tennis.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is number one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Crouch, catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sam West, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: We called him last night.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were going to go up to Lubbock maybe tomorrow for an interview, but it must have been his wife answered the phone and said that
[SPEAKER_01]: His mother living in Haskell was very ill, and they didn't know if they might be told at any moment, so they couldn't make any commitments.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what we were waiting for.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you knew Sam West pretty well then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah, we roomed together six years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he much of a talker?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, not much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you think he'd like to be interviewed, if I could get to see him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, not in the situation where his parents are.
[SPEAKER_00]: How old is his mother?
[SPEAKER_00]: Must be quite old.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, about 90-something.
[SPEAKER_00]: 93.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a fine ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Three dollar stores.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's Pinky Higgins from Dallas, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Les Mallon, he was the infielder.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was the second baseman, shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this was a mission.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the only thing, only... Yeah, that's true.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they taught...
[SPEAKER_00]: This is Pinky Higgins here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Les Mallon.
[SPEAKER_01]: They broke in in 70, in 33.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got that picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: I kept the sporting nose all those years and I cut that one out.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is, well this is from the Astorte and
[SPEAKER_00]: Lynn Stardy.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's Gorms I see there, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Gorms.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's down here somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted Gullick.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Gorms.
[SPEAKER_01]: He lives around here, doesn't he, somewhere?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's dead.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's dead.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where's Gullick from?
[SPEAKER_00]: Gullick?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't know where he came from.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let me see if I can find something.
[SPEAKER_01]: We can find that out later.
[SPEAKER_01]: It says here you made a fine debut for the Browns.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember that game?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yep, sure did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell me a little bit about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in spring training.
[SPEAKER_01]: Go ahead.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was my first one.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is in 33 now then.
[SPEAKER_01]: 32, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't recall, but I think they started me in spring
[SPEAKER_00]: But the first ballgame in spring came in 33.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't know if I've got it here or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you get with him, and I'll get him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't recall anything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oscar Melillo.
[SPEAKER_01]: He did my hair.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember that first game, though?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, it must stand out in your memory.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Three times.
[SPEAKER_00]: I started at St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I was traded to the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I was traded to Philadelphia Athletics.
[SPEAKER_00]: And every time I pitched the first game, I won it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won my first game in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won my first game in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I won my first game in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why did they trade you from St. Louis to Chicago, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was in the deal?
[SPEAKER_00]: As far as I know, it was just cash.
[SPEAKER_00]: She knows more about it than I do.
[SPEAKER_00]: She kept up with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you unhappy to be traded from the Browns or sold?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, but I wanted to pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hadn't traded for a long several years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that a name there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't quite recognize it.
Locke?
Cox.
Thank you.
Oh, is it kind of...
[SPEAKER_00]: too small to participate in sports in high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I wasn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wouldn't let me.
[SPEAKER_01]: How big were you in high school?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was about 145.
[SPEAKER_01]: How tall were you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, about 5'11".
[SPEAKER_00]: That's not too bad for that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just pitched the Sandlot.
[SPEAKER_00]: You didn't play high school ball then?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they had a high school team.
[SPEAKER_00]: A team in the high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wouldn't let me play.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was too small.
[SPEAKER_00]: You played basketball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, but that was Sunday school.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was skinny and tall, like I said.
[SPEAKER_01]: You began to put on some weight after you got out of high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: She fed me too good.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was it like playing with a singer with Browns in the 1930s?
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a nostalgia kicked today about the old St. Louis Browns, really.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a team that never won a pack, except in the war.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't get there until 33.
[SPEAKER_01]: They always seemed to be a second division team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there something discouraging?
[SPEAKER_00]: Old Man Ball, the owner of the ball club, he's the one that wouldn't put out any money.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first money I really got
[SPEAKER_00]: that was worthwhile in those days was at Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: They paid me $400 a month.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then when they sold me a family deal down to St. Louis Browns, well, I had to stay on that $400 deal until the
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't want to send me back with a big salary.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I never did go back.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't get too much gold money either in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: But... What kind of... did you talk to Phil Ball or meet him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Never meet Phil Ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kind of a man of the sea, would you say?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was quiet and stubby and heavy, fat.
[SPEAKER_00]: The only time I would see him, he had a press box for him to watch the ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in spring training, he would come out to watch the workouts at San Antonio.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what we were doing then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he never did say anything bad against anybody, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when you had your contract talks each year, did you deal with Ball or was there some business manager you dealt with?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: There were no business managers back in those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you deal with Ball directly?
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to deal with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd get a letter of your contract in the winter months and then you'd send it back and you didn't like it?
[SPEAKER_01]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't like it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had to.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mainly, after the season in Milwaukee, I was getting $600, Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I came back.
[SPEAKER_00]: I came to St. Louis the next year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they cut me to $400.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I told him, I told Mr. Ball, I said, Mr. Ball, I pitched for your club in Milwaukee, and I got $600.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, I'll give you $600 and more if you can make our team.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he sucked me into that.
[SPEAKER_00]: and still left me all season long.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never did go back to Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got the $400, that's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: But then you got a raise the next year.
[SPEAKER_01]: A little bit, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Up to $600.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't have the money?
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought he was a pretty wealthy man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was wealthy, but he didn't want to spend it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he in the icebox business?
[SPEAKER_01]: What did he have there in St. Louis?
[SPEAKER_01]: hospital or something?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a close friend of Dan Johnson's.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dan Johnson died in Falls Hospital.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was always on the sideline in the box seat.
[SPEAKER_01]: He really liked the game, then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was down at San Antonio or Florida all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we were in either one of those places, he was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, who came after Killifer?
[SPEAKER_01]: You had Roger Swansby for manager for a while, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I wish he wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you like him?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the worst thing that ever lived.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you expect everybody to be as good as he was?
[SPEAKER_01]: Harsh rules, I guess, didn't they?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: had two coaches that he let them run the ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't associate with the ballplayers, except on the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't know, he just was a snotty guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could have hit that ball in his day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could really hit that ball in a day.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never did pitch against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he handle players very well?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he'd let the coaches do everything because he was in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: He would go back under the stands and phone a bookie.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he'd come out an hour later.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's crazy about the horses, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw St. Louis play in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: I grew up in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think 1936, when about a year or so he was managing the team.
[SPEAKER_01]: They played a game in the stadium there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came in and pinch hit, right before he hadn't played golf for a year or so, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was the only time I did get to see Roger Hearn be back.
[SPEAKER_01]: He got a beautiful basic that one time.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Line drive right out of there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he could learn if he wanted to.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess all these great ballplayers aren't very good managers because their players can't play as well as he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's a younger wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a finger broken.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a nice picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: How was that broken?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was pitching, and the line drive came, and I, instead of using my... Gloved hand.
[SPEAKER_00]: My Sutton and Gloved hand, I put my other hand in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it didn't break it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just one of these joints was knocked out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, could you throw as well when it healed?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, after it healed up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe you could throw better.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I couldn't be feeling better because I was doing good out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember what year that was then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Because you had a couple of real good years then.
[SPEAKER_01]: 34 and 35, I believe it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever get hit in the head from a batted ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or in the legs or anything?
[SPEAKER_01]: When you're pitching, you know, with a ball coming off or close?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: The bastards come back through there.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that happened in Milwaukee?
[SPEAKER_01]: This was in Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_01]: That broken finger, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was playing in Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the ball was hit right in front of me.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it hit something and it bounced over my head and I just jabbed it in there and it just bent that.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they sent me home.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is Dorland Braxton's wife.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever hit anybody in the head as a pitcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two times.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did that affect you as a pitcher?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I wasn't through in
[SPEAKER_00]: I've been throwing for it at him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who'd you hit, do you remember one?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, one was Class D ball down in Palestine.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in Tyler.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where he was, and I was pitching there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it hurt that guy pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hit high on the head, so it didn't bother anything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the other one,
[SPEAKER_00]: about in the big time?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was in the B-League down in Palestine.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other one too?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kansas City?
[SPEAKER_00]: Kansas City, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had a fight.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a real, real... Tell me about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I mean, that was...
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit the guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it didn't hurt him, but all those 12 players, they ran after me.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do?
[SPEAKER_00]: I ran most of them off.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did anybody get hurt?
[SPEAKER_01]: Only he and me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a little wife there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, it was one of the big players.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's why they wanted me castrated, put it that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a big hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't have that record, because that was in the minority.
[SPEAKER_01]: But did you get hurt?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did that actually hurt you in the fight?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Most of these fights are just a lot of wild swinging, but sometimes somebody gets hurt.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where'd you hit him?
[SPEAKER_01]: You hit him on the head?
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit him on the side of his head.
[SPEAKER_00]: It just, it mashed his earlobe here, not low, but...
[SPEAKER_00]: It knocked him out or anything?
[SPEAKER_00]: It made him very dizzy.
[SPEAKER_00]: I could throw hard those days, and we don't have any of the kind of hats that they have now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did that upset you?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, pitching after that incident.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I was sorry about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the ball sailed.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't throwing at him at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: But for some reason or other, he was a right-hand hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the ball just faded that way, and he was riding in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he got hit right about here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right in the center.
[SPEAKER_00]: It didn't hurt anything except made him dizzy for a couple of days.
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember Roy Parmalee?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I talked with him and he said he hit a lot of people in the head.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit about five people here in the head.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a very hard thrower and he had poor control.
[SPEAKER_01]: But after every time he hit somebody in the head, they had to take him out of the game because he couldn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: upset him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I remember him on that hard throw-in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with Toledo, probably.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were with Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: Toledo.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they made him slow up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he finally got in the groove.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could throw that ball hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was mostly underhand.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm trying to find one guy that's in here.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 34 and 35, you had pretty good years with the Browns.
[SPEAKER_01]: 10 and 3 and 11 and 8 when they were well below 500, so.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were in the 350 to 400.
[SPEAKER_01]: So how'd you win so many games with such a team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Couldn't win.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't know about them being or not being winning.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had confidence.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the ballplayers on the Browns
[SPEAKER_00]: They liked me and figured that they had a chance to win a ball game any time I stepped out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I did, practically.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, you know... Did you have a favorite catcher at that time in the Browns?
[SPEAKER_01]: or somebody you worked well with?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Jack Crouch was a young, well, I know him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Crouch was a young catcher coming up out of the Texas League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's the day he was playing, this day here.
[SPEAKER_01]: But where's the Browns then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is there anybody there?
[SPEAKER_01]: You liked to have behind the plate when you were pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Raleigh Hensley.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Raleigh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Raleigh King Raleigh.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was in Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_01]: Henry was a pretty good man behind the plate there?
[SPEAKER_01]: He could run and he could hit and catch.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't take care of himself?
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't take care of himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then he finally, later on, got a manager at Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it was Toledo.
[SPEAKER_00]: Toledo.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they fired him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got to drinking again.
[SPEAKER_00]: He can't have himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: He can't have a player.
[SPEAKER_01]: But when Henley was catching for you, would you know just about what to call or would you go over to the players before the game and know what you were going to pitch to them?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you can't always go by that.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, if you can, but if you do it the same way all the time, some of these guys that are good hitters, they'll know what's going to
[SPEAKER_00]: be coming or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh... How'd he fix the Lou Gehrig?
[SPEAKER_00]: Lou Gehrig was one of the easiest, hardest man that hit a ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, I didn't have very much trouble with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you one thing, going back to the... that place, uh...
[SPEAKER_00]: Hickey Higgins was one of my Dallasites.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're speaking of that, good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was pitching St. Louis, and he was third baseman that, uh, athletic, no, yeah, in the athletics at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh, so I, I started pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: First ball, I had three balls out of the, out into the bleachers before I ever
[SPEAKER_00]: ever got to teach me.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first three batters hit home run?
[SPEAKER_00]: The first three batters hit home run.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all of my friends down here in Brownwood, they said, oh my god, he's going to get killed.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then I finished the ball game with no more scores.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won the ball game four to three.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, settling down.
[SPEAKER_01]: The way things can turn around in a game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pinky Higgins was a good hitter and a good third baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you pitch to Al Simmons?
[SPEAKER_00]: Al Simmons?
[SPEAKER_00]: Throw a foot in the bucket.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get too much time to pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't pitch too much against him?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Fill it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I mean when he was with the A's and you were with the Browns.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have any problem with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that a funny batting stance when that left foot is pulled around?
[SPEAKER_01]: It must be tough to pitch to.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was not a good batting stance.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Jimmy Fox, remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember, well, Pinky Higgins, Fox, and one or two more.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cochran.
[SPEAKER_00]: Getting back to this, Cochran, you mentioned that.
[SPEAKER_00]: In spring training in 1933,
[SPEAKER_00]: in San Antonio where you were?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, we worked at 33 down in Florida.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we came back and got into the technology, started in
[SPEAKER_00]: St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: And our first was not our first deal, but Pinky Higgins was on Philadelphia, and I was with the Browns.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was pitching in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the first ball I pitched was hit into the bleachers
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the next ball I pitched, after they came around, they hit another home run in the bleachers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Al Simmons was the third guy up, and he hit his in the right field bleachers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Three home runs on three balls.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I won four to three.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that was your first year then that happened, in 33?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: About 33 he was, his first.
[SPEAKER_01]: You won your first game there with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: What happened in 36 and 37?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or don't you want to talk about those years?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they didn't give me much satisfaction.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you sue for non-support?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, that was the weakest.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they cut your pay after those years?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I was traded.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you were 9 and 17 and 36.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they cut you after that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, they couldn't cut any lower.
[SPEAKER_01]: $400 a month.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was still $400?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it got up to about $600.
[SPEAKER_00]: How do you account for that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just forgot all about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, your earned run average is pretty high in 36.
[SPEAKER_01]: But in 37, your earned run average came down, but you still lost a lot of games.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you were pitching better in 37, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was defense.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pretty poor defense.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't have any shortstops at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stardew, was he then?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Levy?
[SPEAKER_01]: Levy?
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Ollie Bama?
[SPEAKER_00]: He come around yet too?
[SPEAKER_00]: Ollie Bama was a fair second baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: But...
[SPEAKER_00]: It just...
[SPEAKER_00]: They wouldn't give a pitcher a chance.
[SPEAKER_01]: Couldn't field.
[SPEAKER_01]: They tried hard, but... Well...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if they didn't like me or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway...
[SPEAKER_00]: There it is, athletics hit three homers off and on, pulling in four or five balls.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's quite a game.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, it came... George Blayholder came in.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was... Yeah, he...
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he had the screwball or the fadeaway or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he had a shanker.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a good shanker.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was really the founder of the slider, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did the slider and change up.
[SPEAKER_00]: These pictures, more now, they don't know how to mix up a change of pace.
[SPEAKER_00]: They all swirled, swirled, swirled, slider, slider.
[SPEAKER_00]: That slider is going to break your dead gum elbow.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's unnatural motion.
[SPEAKER_01]: But then they don't pitch as long either.
[SPEAKER_00]: They pitch 3 and 8 and somebody comes in and takes their clutch.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you went out to pitch, you were supposed to pitch the whole game, weren't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't have somebody warm enough to come in after 3 and 8.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched 90 percent of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some other pitchers?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Sam Jones in the Browns?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was there at the time that I came in, and he helped me good.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was old then.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't have taken his job, so he still had to help you out.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he just stayed about one year, and then he got sick, and he died about two more years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sam Jones or Sam Gray?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Sam Jones.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because Sam Jones lives only about 25 miles from where we live, you know, in Woodsfield, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know Sam Jones.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, what do you call him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sad Sam Jones.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yankees for a year and the Red Sox, but he was probably...
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess he wasn't with the Browns then.
[SPEAKER_01]: He may have been through by the time you came off.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was an old-time Yankee pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Back in the days of Wade Hoyt and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I was thinking he might have been with the Browns.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Sam Gray was the one that helped you then.
[SPEAKER_00]: He showed me how to make a real curveball fall off the table.
[SPEAKER_00]: That gave me three, four pitches, a good change, a little slider, and a good fastball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He really helped.
[SPEAKER_00]: How was your control overall?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have much problem with control?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too much, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too much.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about a move to first base?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you work on that a little bit?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was going to tell you before we started on this here and here, but I have my little shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 1935, he came up from the Coast League and was a shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he and I got together in spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's in 33, 35.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 35, and he got into spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he and I, we were still in training, and we were playing
[SPEAKER_00]: Terry, he's taking the water.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll get to it before long.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was the shortstop?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it Stordie then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Stordie was third baseman and Levy was shortstop until Alan Strange came.
[SPEAKER_00]: He ran Levy off so he could handle that ball and he knew how to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just came to, he was up in California someplace, and then...
[SPEAKER_01]: He got the pick-off play with Strange?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He and I worked at the pick-off place.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we were playing Bill Terry with John.
[SPEAKER_00]: What do you want to change?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's going to be pretty hard to pick up with the finger.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I don't know if it will drop.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's go over on this side.
[SPEAKER_00]: It won't be much longer.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had this play, and you're on second.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when I'd come down, and I'd either step off or throw, but not to, not to, I don't know what, why we called his name, I just forgot it.
[SPEAKER_00]: time that he had been in Major League.
[SPEAKER_00]: STRANGE.
[SPEAKER_00]: Alan Strange, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we worked and worked in spring training, with me getting down here and Alan over there in the second basement there, like that, and hitting the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was men on bases just practicing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we had a
[SPEAKER_00]: and Bill Terry were managing the Giants, and they were going to play us.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was the pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I came down.
[SPEAKER_00]: The guy got on second base, and I came down, and I whirled around to throw to second, which I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I threw it over the guy's head.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then after that, Bill Terry said, that is a dadgum good play.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm going to get five giants to work on that, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I said, Bill, that's the first time I've thrown it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I could tell him that because he was in the National League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we finally perfected that game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think, I don't have it, but we, I think we got at least 15 to 20 off base.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when I went to
[SPEAKER_00]: Chicago White Sox.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I gave them Luke Apley.
[SPEAKER_00]: I gave him the sign.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then Joe Kill was the first baseman for Chicago there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so I worked out a deal with him, even with somebody on second base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was left-handed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was the man on first and second.
[SPEAKER_00]: He would back off a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when I gave the nod, one, two.
[SPEAKER_00]: Q.
[SPEAKER_00]: You nodded your head?
[SPEAKER_00]: A. I'd come down like this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd throw to the second baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they'd come back with a man on first and second.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I'd come down again, and I had one, two, whirled, and Q was behind the guy, and we got both of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other one started running.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you get him at third?
[SPEAKER_00]: At third, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mickey Cocker, who planned in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mickey was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the same bad gun thing happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: He, I came down, and he had never seen this before.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so, Alan Strange, the only thing he did was, didn't say one, run to the bay.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had Mickey just beat it two feet.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, damn, I'm finding myself a hundred bucks.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never did it anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: On that season, Strange and myself got $18,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: Eighteen of those hauled, either first base or second.
[SPEAKER_00]: That helps them both up pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to have an awful quick motion to do that, to pivot and not balk and throw straight and not too high.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were with the White Sox in 1940 then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: You remember the Jackie Hayes business?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me a little bit about what you remember from that.
[SPEAKER_01]: We've interviewed Hayes, you see.
[SPEAKER_01]: over in Clanton, Alabama.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, sure enough?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, all I know, I hadn't seen him for, oh, 20 years, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was an awful good second baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he could hit the ball and advance the base runners if he was on there.
[SPEAKER_00]: If a baseman was on there, he would either slash a ball
[SPEAKER_00]: or he bunted off him good.
[SPEAKER_00]: He bunted off him good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, this, I heard from Ted Lyons, I guess, that this was, he got a cinder in his eye.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he had that a long time.
[SPEAKER_01]: In spring training in 1940, he got this cinder in his left eye.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's what started it all.
[SPEAKER_01]: That he played half that year, actually, with only one eye.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he behind there when you were pitching, when he played with one eye?
[SPEAKER_00]: In Chicago, we pitched double headers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted would pitch the opening, and I pitched the second.
[SPEAKER_00]: We did that seven times, as far as I can recall.
[SPEAKER_00]: It may have been more.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was all on Sunday.
[SPEAKER_00]: We pitched nothing on Sunday, except on Sunday.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he was playing the first part of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was playing first place football.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he played all that season.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you see the bad eye affecting his play in any way?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: He missed quite a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd slap one down.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd get close enough where he'd slap at it and it wouldn't do any good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the players kind of get troubled by this, that the man out there wasn't really able to see the bomb?
[SPEAKER_00]: The doctors, he was told to go to the doctor in Chicago where we were.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just got deteriorated over, and they just took him off.
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't want to hurt him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he went back to his home after the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: He stayed all season.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a good second baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a good quick wrist on him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Solders, they got it in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess it was 1941 when he was batting practice, just fooling around on the infield.
[SPEAKER_01]: A ground ball hit him and... 1941, 1942, those guys went to athletics.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's when he got... the incident started hitting on his blindness, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Although it didn't happen as quickly.
[SPEAKER_01]: It took a number of years for him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just these crazy little accidents which happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't remind me of those guys anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: The right one went in 1943.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's had a heart attack and... Yeah, he's on his...
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how many pacemakers he's had.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he is suspected of being a pacemaker.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's got a cysts feeding out of his arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, but I think it's... His wife, which is as sweet as she could be, but she was so nervous.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, I remember going to the surgery.
And, uh...
[SPEAKER_01]: They invited him on that night.
[SPEAKER_00]: Earnshaw could get through that ballboard, but I beat him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Q.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: A. I beat him twice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you beat Lefty Grove?
[SPEAKER_00]: A. I don't remember about beating him, but I know I knocked him out of the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you do that?
[SPEAKER_00]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's just saying about a ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, where was I getting out of?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, up to Earnshaw.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, left to go, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was pitching that day and he was pitching against me in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit a line drive and hit him in the head, right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had that long arm and was hitting the...
[SPEAKER_00]: It just hit right in front of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's the first time I ever knocked him out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody...
[SPEAKER_00]: He fell backwards and then staggered.
[SPEAKER_00]: You got a hit?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, I got a base hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he stay in the game?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's one way to get him out of there, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he could really throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you get along with the umpires?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I tried to get along.
[SPEAKER_00]: say you did a good job, stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Most of them were.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't have any problems at all with... Did you get put out of any games?
[SPEAKER_01]: Nope.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's quite an achievement.
[SPEAKER_00]: Most of them, even though they...
[SPEAKER_00]: Even if they didn't do anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a favorite umpire you'd like to have behind the plate when you were pitching, or didn't matter much?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: George, Bill McGowan maybe?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was a ranged angle, but Bill Hubbard.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was so big and could stand over, and he got everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't he miss some low ones though?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was so high up he couldn't stand?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not that I know of.
[SPEAKER_00]: He always came up in St. Louis, our apartment, and have a little drink, just one.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's all he ever drank.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a Texan.
[SPEAKER_01]: He fraternized with the ballplayers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, but they didn't know where he was going.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good friend of ours.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think the umpires... And so was Fred Marbury.
[SPEAKER_01]: Marbury, who was a Roger Peckinpah, told me once that it was Marbury who taught him the real value of a relief pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Back in the 20s, Marbury was one of the first that he knew could really come in and help out.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was before we've gotten to this relief pitching business today where that's what started me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd relieve a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: It didn't make any difference.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wanted to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I had enough rest, I wanted to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you did become a starter after a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: At Chicago, at White Sox, Ted Lyons and myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: I may have said this before.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a doubleheader every Sunday.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Ted Lyons worked the first game, and I worked the second.
[SPEAKER_00]: And eleven ballgames each, we won every one of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Eleven doubleheaders?
[SPEAKER_01]: Eleven doubleheaders.
[SPEAKER_01]: That wasn't all in Chicago, but... That's a great record there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you like Comiskey Park, the pitching, with all those long distances?
[SPEAKER_01]: The long distances there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Couldn't hit them out of the park there very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too much, not too often.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Al Simmons come over to the White Sox when you were there?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or was he there?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was at County Mac all the way through.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, tell me about, was Jimmy Dykes managing?
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_01]: White Sox?
[SPEAKER_01]: A. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you like him?
[SPEAKER_01]: A. Oh, he was great.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was hell-bent, hell-bent for action.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was really, he knew his stuff, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had trained his third base coach and his first base coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could
[SPEAKER_00]: If he wanted to do a deal, I mean, with Jimmy, he'd be sitting like this on the front of the dugout, like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd worry that the other club wouldn't know that that meant signs.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't move his head or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He kind of made motions with his mouth.
[SPEAKER_01]: With his mouth.
[SPEAKER_01]: Out the side of his mouth, which were actually signals.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, actual signals.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pretty good way to do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He handled ballplayers pretty well?
Jimmy?
[SPEAKER_01]: Dykes?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he fraternized the ballplayers all day long.
[SPEAKER_00]: It worked in his case, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a distance that they respected, but they still got along.